<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Family on Liberation Notes</title>
    <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/tags/family/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Family on Liberation Notes</description>
    <image>
      <title>Liberation Notes</title>
      <url>https://blog2.cmwang.net/47</url>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/47</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:16:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make Crispy Plum</title>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/04/make-crispy-plum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/04/make-crispy-plum/</guid>
      <description>Making preserved plums is a straightforward technique that doesn’t call for specialized equipment</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="1.jpeg" alt="image"  />

green plums</p>
<p>The time leading up to and following the Tomb Sweeping Festival has become a significant rite for my family in recent years. We purchase green plums in advance from local farmers in Xinyi Township and use them to create preserved plums. However, due to insufficient rainfall this year, the fruit was slightly less than satisfactory compared to previous years.</p>
<p>Making preserved plums is a straightforward technique that doesn’t call for specialized equipment; rather, it just takes some time and perseverance. One kilogram of green plums, 100 grams of coarse salt, and 600 grams of sugar make up the recipe, which is quite straightforward. Please carry out the actions listed below:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="2.jpeg" alt="image"  />

Rub plums with salt</p>
<ul>
<li>Wash the plums and remove the stems one by one.</li>
<li>Blanch the plums by rubbing them with coarse salt for at least 15 minutes until the surface becomes moist and changes color.</li>
<li>Tap the plums with a hammer one by one until they crack slightly, but do not smash them.</li>
<li>Soak the plums in saltwater for 8 hours, making sure that the water covers them completely.</li>
<li>Pour out the syrup and replace it with fresh syrup every 8 hours.</li>
<li>Repeat step 5 for 3 days until the plums are fully infused with the sugar syrup.</li>
<li>Drain the plums of any remaining bitter syrup, replace it with the final batch of sugar syrup, and let it sit for another 3 days to complete the process.</li>
</ul>
<p>I am grateful to my family for bringing a sense of ceremony into our daily lives. This ritual makes me appreciate the beauty of life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="3.jpeg" alt="image"  />

Crispy Plum</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
