<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reflections on Liberation Notes</title>
    <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/tags/reflections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reflections on Liberation Notes</description>
    <image>
      <title>Liberation Notes</title>
      <url>https://blog2.cmwang.net/47</url>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/47</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:46:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/tags/reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Five Years in the Company</title>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/03/reflections-on-five-years-in-the-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/03/reflections-on-five-years-in-the-company/</guid>
      <description>As I reflect on my five years in this company, I realize how much has happened and how much I have grown</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="1.jpeg" alt="image"  />
</p>
<p>As I reflect on my five years in this company, I realize how much has happened and how much I have grown. From having a supervisor to being a lone ranger, to forming a small team and eventually founding the Nilvana, time has flown by quickly, and I am left wondering where tomorrow will take me.</p>
<p>It seems like just yesterday that I started my journey in this company. I remember the excitement of meeting new colleagues, learning new skills, and finding my place in the organization. Over time, I became more confident and began taking on more responsibilities. I was proud of my accomplishments and the impact that I was making.</p>
<p>However, the road was not always easy. There were times when I faced challenges that made me question my abilities and my decisions. I learned that setbacks and failures are a part of the journey, and they can be a source of growth and resilience.</p>
<p>One of the most significant moments in my journey was the creation of the Nilvana brand. It was a leap of faith, but I knew that I had a vision that could change the game. With the help of a few dedicated team members, we worked tirelessly to bring the brand to life. Seeing it take off and gain recognition was one of the proudest moments of my career.</p>
<p>Looking back on my journey, I realize that time truly flies. It seems like just yesterday that I started, but five years have gone by in a blink of an eye. As I prepare to take on new challenges, I am grateful for the experiences and the lessons that I have learned.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1t8kAbUg4t4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
