<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Liberation Notes</title>
    <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/categories/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Liberation Notes</description>
    <image>
      <title>Liberation Notes</title>
      <url>https://blog2.cmwang.net/47</url>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/47</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:16:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/categories/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Make Crispy Plum</title>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/04/make-crispy-plum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2023 15:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/04/make-crispy-plum/</guid>
      <description>Making preserved plums is a straightforward technique that doesn’t call for specialized equipment</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="1.jpeg" alt="image"  />

green plums</p>
<p>The time leading up to and following the Tomb Sweeping Festival has become a significant rite for my family in recent years. We purchase green plums in advance from local farmers in Xinyi Township and use them to create preserved plums. However, due to insufficient rainfall this year, the fruit was slightly less than satisfactory compared to previous years.</p>
<p>Making preserved plums is a straightforward technique that doesn’t call for specialized equipment; rather, it just takes some time and perseverance. One kilogram of green plums, 100 grams of coarse salt, and 600 grams of sugar make up the recipe, which is quite straightforward. Please carry out the actions listed below:</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="2.jpeg" alt="image"  />

Rub plums with salt</p>
<ul>
<li>Wash the plums and remove the stems one by one.</li>
<li>Blanch the plums by rubbing them with coarse salt for at least 15 minutes until the surface becomes moist and changes color.</li>
<li>Tap the plums with a hammer one by one until they crack slightly, but do not smash them.</li>
<li>Soak the plums in saltwater for 8 hours, making sure that the water covers them completely.</li>
<li>Pour out the syrup and replace it with fresh syrup every 8 hours.</li>
<li>Repeat step 5 for 3 days until the plums are fully infused with the sugar syrup.</li>
<li>Drain the plums of any remaining bitter syrup, replace it with the final batch of sugar syrup, and let it sit for another 3 days to complete the process.</li>
</ul>
<p>I am grateful to my family for bringing a sense of ceremony into our daily lives. This ritual makes me appreciate the beauty of life.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="3.jpeg" alt="image"  />

Crispy Plum</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>You Will Have a Good Day</title>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/04/you-will-have-a-good-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 12:29:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/04/you-will-have-a-good-day/</guid>
      <description>Today you will have a good day. Jesus spoke to them at once, “Don’t be afraid,” he said. “Take courage! I am here!” (Mark 6:50)</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="1.jpeg" alt="image"  />
</p>
<p>Today you will have a good day. Jesus spoke to them at once, “Don’t be afraid,” he said. “Take courage! I am here!” (Mark 6:50)</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="2.png" alt="image"  />
</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Five Years in the Company</title>
      <link>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/03/reflections-on-five-years-in-the-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 14:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog2.cmwang.net/en/posts/2023/03/reflections-on-five-years-in-the-company/</guid>
      <description>As I reflect on my five years in this company, I realize how much has happened and how much I have grown</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="1.jpeg" alt="image"  />
</p>
<p>As I reflect on my five years in this company, I realize how much has happened and how much I have grown. From having a supervisor to being a lone ranger, to forming a small team and eventually founding the Nilvana, time has flown by quickly, and I am left wondering where tomorrow will take me.</p>
<p>It seems like just yesterday that I started my journey in this company. I remember the excitement of meeting new colleagues, learning new skills, and finding my place in the organization. Over time, I became more confident and began taking on more responsibilities. I was proud of my accomplishments and the impact that I was making.</p>
<p>However, the road was not always easy. There were times when I faced challenges that made me question my abilities and my decisions. I learned that setbacks and failures are a part of the journey, and they can be a source of growth and resilience.</p>
<p>One of the most significant moments in my journey was the creation of the Nilvana brand. It was a leap of faith, but I knew that I had a vision that could change the game. With the help of a few dedicated team members, we worked tirelessly to bring the brand to life. Seeing it take off and gain recognition was one of the proudest moments of my career.</p>
<p>Looking back on my journey, I realize that time truly flies. It seems like just yesterday that I started, but five years have gone by in a blink of an eye. As I prepare to take on new challenges, I am grateful for the experiences and the lessons that I have learned.</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1t8kAbUg4t4" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
